CV: Jostein Dyrseth

josdyr@gmail.com +44 7543 554950 josdyr.github.io

Personal Statement

Being open-minded to new ideas, methods and technologies drives me to constantly learn and strive in order to be an expert in the rapidly adapting computer industry. I am a clear communicator and conscientious with the ability to accomplish competing tasks to a high standard whilst meeting deadlines. I value strong, open and honest relationships with all stakeholders to the end of a project and beyond. Self-motivation is a strength of mine that allows me to offer the dynamism to both work together well in a team as well as independently.

Soft Skills

Positive team player, colleague and friend

Easily and quickly accessible

Fast and definite communicator

Ability to network

Confident with presentations and public speaking

Integrity

Self-motivated

Strong passion to achieve new and relevant talent

Meets deadlines

Hard Skills

Python (TensorFlow, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib)

C, C++ & C#

Relational & Object-Relational Databases (SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL & NoSQL)

Go

Java

Test driven development, continuous integration and agile workflow

Unix & GIT Version Control

Docker & AWS

Django, Flask

HTML & CSS, JavaScript, Jinja2

Education

Aug 2015 - Present: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with Honours

Edinburgh Napier University, Scotland

Aug 2014 - Apr 2015: Physics & Higher Mathematics

AOF, Norway

Aug 2013 - Jun 2014: 3D Design And Animation

Noroff University College, Norway

Sep 2012 - May 2013: Bethel Bible School

California, USA

Aug 2009 - May 2012: High School

Lundeneset VGS, Norway

Experience

June 2018 - Aug 2018: Internship: IoT Content Management System Web Platform

Edinburgh Napier University, Scotland

• Developed an Internet of Things web user platform

• Familiarised myself with the Django CMS Web Framework

• Users, Admins and Site administration

• Learned to build, configure and migrate data with PostgreSQL Backend

Configured and containerised the web app using Docker

Sep 2014 - Aug 2015: Customer Service and Warehouse Assistant

Jula Retail Store, Norway

Achievements

Sep 2017: Awarded best Hackathon: Heatmap of Traffic Accidents in Scotland with

Parameter Search

Edinburgh Napier University, Scotland

 Worked together in a team to organise, brainstorm and develop a web app with a map of traffic accidents

• Parameter search

Filtering

Award: Best 3D Modelling & Design

Noroff University College, Norway

 Blender & Maya software used to animate, model, texture, light and render character

Interests

Having visited and lived in cultures of various nations, I am an energetic, hands-on and engaged individual who can adapt to any situation or workplace, with a can-do attitude. I like to travel and see new cities around the world.

Competitive sports like football, tag or tennis with friends and acquaintances always puts me in a good mood. I like to go for a run in the city and I also visit the gym rather frequently. Reading a good book once in a while either to learn something new or just to engage myself in a good story or debate is compelling. Occasionally I invite friends and relatives over to enjoy a chatty and lively evening, relaxing with a fascinating documentary, some snacks, a coffee or a good craft beer.

Beliefs & Vision

I believe in modularity, readability, reusability and simplicity

I believe that often «less is more»

I believe in a layered software architecture

I believe data is the new oil

I believe that one should strive for efficiency

I believe in good work ethics

I believe in positivity

I believe that anything is possible

I believe in dreaming Big